Pham Huy Hoang (Harry Pham) - Full Stack Developer

Phone: +65 9373.4483 / Email: huyhoang8a5@gmail.com LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/huyhoangpham92

SUMMARY

I'm a full stack developer with 6 years of experience in Web Development (which includes 4 years of experience in Modern Front-End Web Development and 4 years of .NET related technologies), with good knowledge of Object-Oriented Analysis and Design, Architecture Design, and Design Patterns.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Programming Languages:
 - JavaScript, C#.NET
- Frameworks/ Platforms:
 - ReactJS, AngularJS, NodeJS
 - Webpack, Babel, ES6
 - ASP.NET MVC, Web API
 - Entity Framework
 - jQuery, Twitter Bootstrap

- Database Management Systems:
 - PostgreSQL, MS SQL Server, MySQL
- Version Control:
 - Git, TFS, SVN,
- Foreign Languages:
 - IELTS: 7.5

Others:

- Good understanding of OOP methodologies, SOLID principles, design patterns
- Hands-on experience with Cloud Computing Platform: Azure & Google Cloud Platform
- Good understanding of OOP methodologies, SOLID principles, design patterns
- Experience in setting up CI/CD and implement DevOps best practices

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

90Seconds (Singapore) - Lead Front-end Engineer

02/2019 - Now

Project: 90 Seconds Platform & Marketplace (5 members)

- **Description**: 90 Seconds is the premiere global video creation platform, enabling brands to create quality videos anywhere in the world.
- Technologies: ReactJS, TypeScript, Jest & react-testing-library, GraphQL (React-Apollo on Front-end, Ruby on Rails + GraphQL on back-end)
- Responsibilities:
 - o Define the architecture, coding convention, and setup CI/CD build system for all front-end projects (includes linter, unit test, build script)
 - o Implement important section of the front-end application. Reviewing Code & Mentoring Junior members of the team to ensure code quality
 - o Communicate with Product Owner and stakeholders (CEO & Marketing Department) to create product roadmap.
 - Make estimation on the product roadmap. Make the roadmap into actionable ticket and assign them to members of my team

Algomerchant (Singapore) - Senior Front-end Engineer Project: Auto Invest (6 members)

08/2017 - 02/2019

- **Description**: A automated-trading system that help users manage they trading portfolio, automatically executed trade by following signals high-profit strategy.
- Technologies: Electron, AngularJS 1.x, Gulp, ES6, ESLint, Firebase, NodeJS
- Responsibilities:
 - o Define the architecture, coding convention, and setup CI/CD system for the whole front-end of the project (includes linter, unit test, build script)
 - o Design database schema, implement back-end services and the trading signal execution engine
 - o Maintaining Algomerchant's legacy system. Refactoring code, and re-architecting the monolith service into many micro-services.

Lancaster University ISS (UK) - Full Stack Developer

02/2016 - 07/2017

Project: iLancaster (10 members)

- **Description**: A free mobile app delivering Lancaster University services, resources, and information at your fingertips whenever you want them, from wherever you are.
- Technologies: React & Redux, Webpack, Babel, Jest, ES6, ESLint, ASP.NET MVC 4
- Responsibilities:
 - o Design UX/UI and implement additional functionalities (both back-end and front-end) based on the requirements from stakeholders
 - o Design database schema and implement back-end services for the iLancaster app
 - o Collaborate with team leader to define and improve the team's workflow, which decreases 40% time to deploy new functionality and reduce bugs related to configuration

ASWIG Solutions - Software Engineer

09/2014 - 09/2015

Project: Foundation (6 members)

- **Project Description**: A system which serves as a gateway, checks the authentication and authorization of the users from other applications.
- Technologies: AngularJS 1.x, jQuery, ASP.NET MVC 4
- Responsibilities:
 - o Communicate with customers and teammates to clarify requirements
 - o Develop key modules of the system. Implement an input validation framework that saved around 20% of the development time of other functionalities
 - o Write key technical documents and mentor new members of the team

FPT Software Ho Chi Minh - Junior Developer

01/2014 - 08/2014

Project: Nebula – Simulator (12 members)

- **Project Description**: A system simulates the process of constructing an oil well. The purpose of the system is to help to train junior petroleum engineers.
- Responsibilities:
 - o Develop and fix the application's defect based on requirements
 - o Develop small modules of the system
 - o Prepare documents and technical guide for developers joining in the middle of the project

EDUCATION

Lancaster University (United Kingdom)

09/2015 - 09/2017

- Studying MSc International Innovation Computer Science pathway.
- Degree grade: Distinction GPA 75.78%.

FPT University Ho Chi Minh (Vietnam)

11/2010 - 01/2014

Studying Software Engineering.

- Degree grade: Good GPA 88% (Equivalent to 1st in the UK).
- Top 5 graduated students in 2014.

PASTIMES AND ACTIVITIES

- I am keen on reading books, IT blogs, Medium, and Quora in my free time. My favourite books are: Clean Code, Head First Design Pattern, C# in Depth, Working with Legacy Code.
- My other hobby is blogging, as I am the author of a Vietnamese IT blog called toidicodedao.com, where I share my working experience and knowledge to other developers. My blog is one of the biggest IT blogs in Vietnam with more than 150.000 views monthly.
- I also participate in <u>stackoverflow.com</u> an international Q&A site for programmers: https://stackoverflow.com/users/4201323/huy-hoang-pham
- In my free time, I also work on some pet projects. They can be found at my online CV cv.toidicodedao.com and my GitHub profile https://github.com/conanak99